Mustapha Lateb

Site: https://mlateb.github.io Email: mustapha.lateb@gmail.com GitHub: https://github.com/mlateb

Stackoverflow: https://stackoverflow.com/cv/mlateb

Twitter: https://twitter.com/MustaphaLateb

Adress: Chania, Greece

CURRENT POSITION

Researcher at the *Geoinformation in Environmental Management* departement of the *Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania* MAICh.

I use Satellite Remote Sensing and GIS, Image processing, Machine Learning, Statistics, Timeseries Analysis in order to solve Ecolocal issues, mainly Landcover change and Forestfire mapping.

Focuse is on **Open Source** solutions, **Python geospatial libraries**, **QGIS**, **linux**, **Version controle** systems. Commercial tools are also used.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS:

Geospatial processing: Python (rasterio, pandas, numpy, matplotlib, seaborn,

geopandas, shapely, ...)

Database: SQL

Version controle: Git, GitHub Web design: HTML, CSS, Markdown

Softwares: QGIS, eCognition, ArcGIS, ERDAS, MapInfo

Operating systems: Linux & Windows

EDUCATION

• 2016 - current : *PhD student*, **Geoinformation applied to Plant Ecology**, UMMTO. Algeria

Topic: Multitemporal landcover mapping

• 2013 - 2016 : *M. Sc. Degree (2 years)*, **Geoinformation in Environmental Management**, MAICh, Greece

Thesis topic: " Development of an object-based classification model for monitoring treeline shifting, using aerial photography"

• 2011-2014 : Magister degree (2 years), Applied Plant Ecology and Environmental Management, UMMTO, Algeria

Thesis topic: "Study of oak hybridisation using Geometric Morphometric (Landmark Method)"

• 2006 - 2011 : *Ingénieur d'Etat (5 years)*, **Plant ecology and Environment** UMMTO, Algeria

Thesis topic: "Inventory of oak gallings and evaluation their impact on forest stands"

• 2008 - 2011 : Senior Technician (3 years), **Database Management** INSFP, Algeria *Thesis topic:* "Creation of a Dynamic Website"

COMMUNICATION AND ORGANISATION

Used to work in multicultural and multidisciplinary teams. Open to new ideas and challenges. I was in the organising committee of the following conferences:

- 38th Annual EARSeL Symposium
- 11th EARSeL Forest Fires SIG Workshop

OTHER WORK EXPERIENCE

- Mar 2013-Sep 2013 : **Energy Steward** at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria
- Nov 2011-Feb 2013: Quality Assurance Technician at Aldaph (Novo Nordisk A/S),TO, Algeria
 Novo Nordisk A/S Global healthcare company headquartered in Denmark.

LANGUAGES

Kabyle: Mother tongue

French: Fluent
Arabic: Fluent
Greek: Beginner